<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Monmouth University CSSE News and Events</title><link>http://rockhopper.monmouth.edu/~s1049128/cssenews.rss.xml</link><description>Monmouth University's Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering News and Events</description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 10:15:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>SE Senior Wins University’s October TECHPitch Event and Competes in NJ TechLaunch BullPen #11</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#kreda1</link><description>
Software Engineering Senior, Kalyna Reda, and her startup, MedEd, won the October 2018 Monmouth University TECHPitch Event. She then represented Monmouth University in New Jersey’s premier investor pitch event, TechLaunch Bullpen #11, on November 14, 2018, competing for investor/entrepreneur support and $20,000 of professional services. The TechLaunch event was held in Pozycki Auditorium.
About MedEd: MedEd is a mobile application that will improve the accuracy and quality of paper evaluations that track the progress of medical residentsâ training, in real time.
About BullPen: BullPen is a bi-monthly series of pitch events similar to Shark Tank where three or four mentored tech companies present to a mixed audience and panel of investors and entrepreneurs in the New Jersey metropolitan area. Audience participation is encouraged. Presenters receive valuable constructive feedback from an experienced panel of investors and entrepreneurs. Pre-BullPen mentoring is provided and Followup mentoring is encouraged, with funding opportunities on the horizon.
</description></item><item><title>SE Graduate in Spring 2018 Issue of Monmouth Magazine</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#skhalifah1</link><description>
Saoud Khalifah (BSSE 2013, MSSE 2014) was featured in the Spring 2018 issue of Monmouth Magazine, in an article titled, “Consumer Protector: Tired of getting duped by fake product reviews online? Saoud Khalifahâs website can help you shop smarter.” In the article, he recalls how his personal on-line shopping experiences as a student led to his idea to develop Fakespot.com, “a website that automatically scans reviews to give consumers better insight about the products they want to purchase.” He gives an overview of how Fakespot works, including the use of natural language processing to better comprehend and evaluate online product reviews.
</description></item><item><title>2018 High School Programming Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hsprogcontest2018</link><description>
The CSSE department and IEEE/ACM Student Chapter hosted the 2018 High School Programming Competition on Friday, February 23, 2018. Twenty four teams of high school students from Middletown South, Ocean Township, the Freehold Regional School District, the Toms River School District, Henry Hudson, Red Bank Regional, and Donovan Catholic participated in this event. Industry sponsors IBM, Commvault and Sparta Systems provided prizes for the winning teams, and the Macaluso Group donated computing-related books for all teams.
</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in Fall 2017 School of Science Graduate Spotlight</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#jbuck2017</link><description>
Jessica Buck (BSCS 2014) was the featured alumna in the Fall 2017/Winter 2018 School of Science newsletter. She is a current business analyst for MedForce. She also worked previously as a software developer and computer programmer/analyst for other healthcare companies. She recalls her journey from earning an Associates of Arts degree in English at Brookdale to a Bachelors in CS at Monmouth, all while balancing school and motherhood. She also recalls the supportive atmosphere and hands-on learning opportunities she experienced at Monmouth.
</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in Fall 2017 Issue of Monmouth Magazine</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#janastasio1</link><description>
Jessica Anastasio (BSCS 2016) was featured in the Fall 2017 issue of Monmouth Magazine, in an article titled, “5 Steps To Landing Your Dream Tech Job: Buzzfeedâs Jessica Anastasio shares her recipe for success.” In the article, she recounts the challenges she faced and overcame as a female CS major. She also offers practical advise to help students break into and advance in careers in technology.
</description></item><item><title>Department Hosts Random Hacks of Kindness Junior: Kids Coding for A Cause</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#rhokjr2017</link><description>
The Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, in conjunction with Random Hacks of Kindness Junior (RHoKJr), hosted its first Random Hacks of Kindness Junior: Kids Coding for A Cause event on October 28, 2017 in the School of Science atrium.
Nearly 50 female students in grades four through eight participated in the daylong event. Students were divided into 13 teams, with each team working on behalf of a local nonprofit organization, guided by a computer science and software engineering student and/or an alumna mentor.
</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in Summer 2017 Issue of Monmouth Magazine</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#licata1</link><description>
Giuseppe Licata (BSCS 2017) was featured in the Summer 2017 issue of Monmouth Magazine, in an article titled, “Bot Man: Giuseppe Licata is coding his way to the top, one chatbot at a time.” He discusses the rising importance of chatbots in online services. The article mentions his contributions as part of the winning team in the February 2017 RightAnswers Chatbot Challenge at MU.
</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in 2017 School of Science Graduate Spotlight</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#campos1</link><description>
Taylor Campos (BSCS 2017) was featured in a 2017 School of Science Graduate Spotlight. She recounts what factors attracted her to Monmouth University, why MU was a good fit for her and how MU prepared her to be successful. She also discusses her experiences as a IEEE/ACM chapter officer and School of Science Peer Mentor.
</description></item><item><title>CSSE Students Participate in RightAnswers Customer Service Chatbot Challenge</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#rightanswers2017</link><description>
CSSE students Mada Almansoor, Phil DiMarco, Darius Jenkins and Giuseppe Licata participated in interdisciplinary teams that were finalists in the RightAnswers Customer Service Chatbot challenge. The chatbot development competition was comprised of Monmouth University business and computer science/software engineering students. Their task was to develop software that delivers automated customer service support through messaging platforms.
</description></item><item><title>2016 High School Programming Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hsprogcontest2016</link><description>
The CSSE department and IEEE/ACM Student Chapter hosted the 2016 High School Programming Competition on Friday March 4, 2016. Twenty teams of 3 students from 10 area high schools participated in this event.
</description></item><item><title>IEEE/ACM Student Chapter Receives NCWIT Student Seed Fund Gift from Google.org</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#googleaward2016</link><description>
Monmouth University’s IEEE/ACM Student Chapter has been awarded a National Center for Women and Information Technology (NCWIT) Student Seed Fund gift of $3,000. This gift, sponsored by Google.org, will be used to create an Association for Computing Machinery Committee on Women in Computing (ACM-W) chapter on campus. Student chapters of ACM-W serve to increase recruitment and retention of women in computing fields at the university level, and will offer students activities and projects that aim to improve the working and learning environments for women in computing.
</description></item><item><title>Faculty Member and 5 Students Attend 2015 Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Conference in Houston, TX</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#gracehopper2015</link><description>
For the second year in a row, Monmouth faculty and students have been part of the worldâs largest gathering of women technologists at the Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Conference. Two students, Taylor Klodowski and Jessica Anastasio, were among the 26% of applicants to receive a GHC Scholarship Grant, providing full support for attendance at the 2015 event. The Computer Science &amp; Software Engineering Department and The School of Science provided support for three additional students, Veronica Granite, Taylor Campos, and AbdulMuhsin Al-Kandari to join the scholarship recipients and Department Chair Prof. Jamie Kretsch at the event. All students are actively involved in the student chapter of the IEEE/ACM.
</description></item><item><title>Inaugural High School Programming Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hsprogcontest2015</link><description>
The Monmouth University IEEE/ACM Student Chapter is hosting their inaugural High School Programming Competition on Thursday May 14, 2015. One 3-person team can be registered per school. $40 registration for the team and advisor includes continental breakfast and lunch. Prizes will be awarded.
Contact: Prof. Jamie Kretsch
</description></item><item><title>CSSE Faculty and Students Participating in Hour of Code</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hourofcode2014</link><description>
Monmouth Universityâs Computer Science and Software Engineering Department is encouraging everyone to join in on the largest learning event in history: The Hour of Code.
Students and faculty from the department will be visiting several area schools to help kick-off their Hour of Code activities, and we have scheduled several Hour of Code sessions on our West Long Branch campus. One Hour of Code session on Wednesday Dec. 10 is for current University students, and sessions on Thursday and Friday are for the community where parents and children can complete an Hour of Code activity together. Monmouth University students and faculty will be available to answer questions as participants go through the self-guided coding experience.
The Hour of Code is a campaign to prove that regardless of age, race or gender, anyone can learn how to not just consume, but build the technologies of the future.
</description></item><item><title>CSSE Juniors Win Awards At Second Annual Marathon Hackathon</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hackathon0614</link><description>
Two CSSE Juniors, Justin Schlemm and Taylor Klodowski recently earned a second-place award at Marathon Data Systemsâ second annual âMarathon Hackathon,â which was held June 7 and 8 at Marathon Data Systemsâ office in Neptune.
They also received a $400 prize for creating a mobile application to connect volunteers to relevant charity events. Their application, ChariTEA (technology, effort, action), allows charities to post times, dates and skill-set requirements when volunteers are needed. Volunteers can also post their skills, register for assignments and maintain a personal profile to keep a record of hours worked, which can be accessible to charity organizations as well.
The Hackathon lasted over 26 hours and challenged teams of software developers from the tri-state area to create a fully functional application from scratch during the allotted time. The application was to focus on connecting volunteers, individuals or organizations to relevant local charity events.
</description></item><item><title>IEEE/ACM Student Chapter attends IEEE Region 1 Student Conference at NJIT</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#ieee0314</link><description>
On March 29th, 2014, the IEEE/ACM student chapter of Monmouth University attended the IEEE Region 1 Student Conference at NJIT. At the conference Jake Vernon, President, had the opportunity to speak on behalf of the chapter during the Student Chapter Showcase. Following the showcase was the micro-mouse competition, where Sidhdhesh Patel, James Blessing, Justin Schlemm, Zixi Li, and Jake Vernon were able to display all their hard work that had been put into the device that they had been developing for months. Unfortunately the micro-mouse hardware did not function as intended, but the team was still asked to present their micro-mouse to all the other participants. Lead Developer, Sidhdhesh Patel, Vice President, lead the discussion and answered many software-related questions since the MU IEEE/ACM chapter was the only chapter present with a Software Engineering Background. During the awards dinner at the end of the conference, the chapter received an award for their participation in the Student Chapter Showcase.
</description></item><item><title>CS Grad Student Featured in Faces of Monmouth</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#delfattore1</link><description>
Christopher Del Fattore (BSCS, 2013) has a featured profile in Faces of Monmouth. As part of his Spring 2013 senior project, Chris and his team developed “The Mark,” a Java application allowing users to comment on PDF documents. The project earned his team the Dean’s Award of Excellence for Undergraduate Research at MU’s Student Research Conference. After earning his bachelor’s degree in computer science, he landed a job at ForeFront, Inc., a Fair Haven, NJ tech firm that specializes in cloud computing-services hosted over the Internet. He credits Monmouth for this opportunity. Also, in Fall 2013, he started in the computer science graduate program in pursuit of his master’s degree.
</description></item><item><title>CSSE Department to Offer New Master of Science in Information Systems Degree</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#msis</link><description>
The Monmouth University Board of Trustees has approved the Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering’s proposed Master of Science in Information Systems (MS-IS) degree program. The program is scheduled to be implemented starting in the Fall semester of 2014. The mission of the MS-IS program will be to integrate information technology and business management at the graduate level to provide well-trained students who would enter and be successful in local IT sectors. The goals of the program include the following:
to prepare information system designers, developers, and/or administrators for successful employment;
to produce scholarship in the area of information systems; and
to provide the surrounding community with a viable opportunity to augment current information technology management skills with new and systematic knowledge.
The Monmouth MS-IS program is designed to be interdisciplinary in that it brings together the fields of computer science, software engineering, and business management. The curriculum is designed to provide a sound basis for continued learning in the field beyond graduation. The degree program is designed to be either full time or part time and to prepare students for employment in the IT sector as information system developers or administrators. The program allows students to choose one of two tracks: the Technology Track or the Management Track. The Technology Track will emphasize the software life cycle, while the Management Track will emphasize information technology management and business strategic management.
</description></item><item><title>Two Teams of CS Seniors Receive Dean’s Award of Excellence in Undergraduate Research</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#deansAwardSp13</link><description>
The following two teams of CS Seniors have received the School of Science Dean’s Award of Excellence in Undergraduate Research in integrative research:
Steven Cregan, Garrett Haas, Gage Jackson, Patrick McDonald
Project Title: Put-A-Tag: A Generic Tagging Tool
Faculty Mentor: Dr. Cui Yu
Christopher Del Fattore, Bruce Lukens, Jesse Rosero
Project Title: The Mark: A Commenting Application
Faculty Mentor: Dr. Cui Yu
They received the awards at the University’s Annual Student Research Conference, sponsored by the School of Science. The conference gives students the opportunity to present their work via poster presentations to their peers, faculty members, and friends and family.
</description></item><item><title>Team of Current and Former CSSE Dept. Students Wins 24-Hour Hackathon To Benefit Jersey Shore Recovery From Super Storm Sandy</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hackathon0413</link><description>
On April 28-29, three of our Monmouth CSSE students participated in–and won–a 24-hour Hackathon called the Jersey Shore Comeback-A-Thon. Gary Kagan is currently an undergraduate Software Engineering major at Monmouth University, and Cory Cardio received his MS last year. Together with Margaret Kim, also a past CSSE student, they formed “Team Mango” and worked through the night on Saturday, developing a new and novel mobile app.
The theme of the event was Jersey Shore Recovery from Super Storm Sandy and featured several talks by local businesspeople describing challenges that the Shore has faced in the past six months. The Hackathon challenge was to create a software application that could help businesses and local communities recover over the upcoming summer months. Team Mango created a “crowd-sourced application where members of the community could give and receive up-to-the-minute pertinent information in the event of a disaster like Hurricane Sandy, such as which businesses had electricity. Since connecting to the Internet was an issue for many during the storm, the application would include a texting component so users could update others as well as receive updates on their phone even if they did not have a Smartphone or could not get internet access.”
When the dust cleared and the sun rose, the team of judges named Team Mango the winning team and awarded them the $1,000 first-prize. The event was sponsored by Marathon Data and was held at CoWerks in Asbury Park.
</description></item></channel></rss>