<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Monmouth University CSSE News and Events</title><link>http://rockhopper.monmouth.edu/~s1049128/cssenews.rss.xml</link><description>Monmouth University's Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering News and Events</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 11:58:20 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>SE Senior Wins University’s October TECHPitch Event and Competes in NJ TechLaunch BullPen #11</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#kreda1</link><description> 


Software Engineering Senior, Kalyna Reda, and her startup, MedEd, won the October 2018 Monmouth University TECHPitch Event. She then represented Monmouth University in New Jersey’s premier investor pitch event, TechLaunch Bullpen #11, on November 14, 2018, competing for investor/entrepreneur support and $20,000 of professional services. The TechLaunch event was held in Pozycki Auditorium.</description></item><item><title>SE Graduate in Spring 2018 Issue of Monmouth Magazine</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#skhalifah1</link><description>Saoud Khalifah (BSSE 2013, MSSE 2014) was featured in the Spring 2018 issue of Monmouth Magazine, in an article titled, “Consumer Protector: Tired of getting duped by fake product reviews online? Saoud Khalifahâs website can help you shop smarter.” In the article, he recalls how his personal on-line shopping experiences as a student led to his idea to develop Fakespot.</description></item><item><title>2018 High School Programming Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hsprogcontest2018</link><description>The CSSE department and IEEE/ACM Student Chapter hosted the 2018 High School Programming Competition on Friday, February 23, 2018. Twenty four teams of high school students from Middletown South, Ocean Township, the Freehold Regional School District, the Toms River School District, Henry Hudson, Red Bank Regional, and Donovan Catholic participated in this event.</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in Fall 2017 School of Science Graduate Spotlight</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#jbuck2017</link><description>Jessica Buck (BSCS 2014) was the featured alumna in the Fall 2017/Winter 2018 School of Science newsletter. She is a current business analyst for MedForce. She also worked previously as a software developer and computer programmer/analyst for other healthcare companies. She recalls her journey from earning an Associates of Arts degree in English at Brookdale to a Bachelors in CS at Monmouth, all while balancing school and motherhood.</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in Fall 2017 Issue of Monmouth Magazine</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#janastasio1</link><description>Jessica Anastasio (BSCS 2016) was featured in the Fall 2017 issue of Monmouth Magazine, in an article titled, “5 Steps To Landing Your Dream Tech Job: Buzzfeedâs Jessica Anastasio shares her recipe for success.” In the article, she recounts the challenges she faced and overcame as a female CS major. She also offers practical advise to help students break into and advance in careers in technology.</description></item><item><title>Department Hosts Random Hacks of Kindness Junior: Kids Coding for A Cause</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#rhokjr2017</link><description>The Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, in conjunction with Random Hacks of Kindness Junior (RHoKJr), hosted its first Random Hacks of Kindness Junior: Kids Coding for A Cause event on October 28, 2017 in the School of Science atrium.
Nearly 50 female students in grades four through eight participated in the daylong event.</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in Summer 2017 Issue of Monmouth Magazine</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#licata1</link><description>Giuseppe Licata (BSCS 2017) was featured in the Summer 2017 issue of Monmouth Magazine, in an article titled, “Bot Man: Giuseppe Licata is coding his way to the top, one chatbot at a time.” He discusses the rising importance of chatbots in online services. The article mentions his contributions as part of the winning team in the February 2017 RightAnswers Chatbot Challenge at MU.</description></item><item><title>CS Graduate in 2017 School of Science Graduate Spotlight</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#campos1</link><description>Taylor Campos (BSCS 2017) was featured in a 2017 School of Science Graduate Spotlight. She recounts what factors attracted her to Monmouth University, why MU was a good fit for her and how MU prepared her to be successful. She also discusses her experiences as a IEEE/ACM chapter officer and School of Science Peer Mentor.</description></item><item><title>CSSE Students Participate in RightAnswers Customer Service Chatbot Challenge</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#rightanswers2017</link><description>CSSE students Mada Almansoor, Phil DiMarco, Darius Jenkins and Giuseppe Licata participated in interdisciplinary teams that were finalists in the RightAnswers Customer Service Chatbot challenge. The chatbot development competition was comprised of Monmouth University business and computer science/software engineering students. Their task was to develop software that delivers automated customer service support through messaging platforms.</description></item><item><title>2016 High School Programming Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hsprogcontest2016</link><description>The CSSE department and IEEE/ACM Student Chapter hosted the 2016 High School Programming Competition on Friday March 4, 2016. Twenty teams of 3 students from 10 area high schools participated in this event.</description></item><item><title>IEEE/ACM Student Chapter Receives NCWIT Student Seed Fund Gift from Google.org</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#googleaward2016</link><description>Monmouth University’s IEEE/ACM Student Chapter has been awarded a National Center for Women and Information Technology (NCWIT) Student Seed Fund gift of $3,000. This gift, sponsored by Google.org, will be used to create an Association for Computing Machinery Committee on Women in Computing (ACM-W) chapter on campus.</description></item><item><title>Faculty Member and 5 Students Attend 2015 Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Conference in Houston, TX</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#gracehopper2015</link><description>For the second year in a row, Monmouth faculty and students have been part of the worldâs largest gathering of women technologists at the Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Conference. Two students, Taylor Klodowski and Jessica Anastasio, were among the 26% of applicants to receive a GHC Scholarship Grant, providing full support for attendance at the 2015 event.</description></item><item><title>Inaugural High School Programming Competition</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hsprogcontest2015</link><description>The Monmouth University IEEE/ACM Student Chapter is hosting their inaugural High School Programming Competition on Thursday May 14, 2015. One 3-person team can be registered per school. $40 registration for the team and advisor includes continental breakfast and lunch. Prizes will be awarded.
Contact: Prof.</description></item><item><title>CSSE Faculty and Students Participating in Hour of Code</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hourofcode2014</link><description>Monmouth Universityâs Computer Science and Software Engineering Department is encouraging everyone to join in on the largest learning event in history: The Hour of Code.
Students and faculty from the department will be visiting several area schools to help kick-off their Hour of Code activities, and we have scheduled several Hour of Code sessions on our West Long Branch campus. One Hour of Code session on Wednesday Dec.</description></item><item><title>CSSE Juniors Win Awards At Second Annual Marathon Hackathon</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hackathon0614</link><description>Two CSSE Juniors, Justin Schlemm and Taylor Klodowski recently earned a second-place award at Marathon Data Systemsâ second annual âMarathon Hackathon,â which was held June 7 and 8 at Marathon Data Systemsâ office in Neptune.
They also received a $400 prize for creating a mobile application to connect volunteers to relevant charity events. Their application, ChariTEA (technology, effort, action), allows charities to post times, dates and skill-set requirements when volunteers are needed.</description></item><item><title>IEEE/ACM Student Chapter attends IEEE Region 1 Student Conference at NJIT</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#ieee0314</link><description>On March 29th, 2014, the IEEE/ACM student chapter of Monmouth University attended the IEEE Region 1 Student Conference at NJIT. At the conference Jake Vernon, President, had the opportunity to speak on behalf of the chapter during the Student Chapter Showcase.</description></item><item><title>CS Grad Student Featured in Faces of Monmouth</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#delfattore1</link><description>Christopher Del Fattore (BSCS, 2013) has a featured profile in Faces of Monmouth. As part of his Spring 2013 senior project, Chris and his team developed “The Mark,” a Java application allowing users to comment on PDF documents. The project earned his team the Dean’s Award of Excellence for Undergraduate Research at MU’s Student Research Conference. After earning his bachelor’s degree in computer science, he landed a job at ForeFront, Inc.</description></item><item><title>CSSE Department to Offer New Master of Science in Information Systems Degree</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#msis</link><description>The Monmouth University Board of Trustees has approved the Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering’s proposed Master of Science in Information Systems (MS-IS) degree program. The program is scheduled to be implemented starting in the Fall semester of 2014. The mission of the MS-IS program will be to integrate information technology and business management at the graduate level to provide well-trained students who would enter and be successful in local IT sectors.</description></item><item><title>Two Teams of CS Seniors Receive Dean’s Award of Excellence in Undergraduate Research</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#deansAwardSp13</link><description>The following two teams of CS Seniors have received the School of Science Dean’s Award of Excellence in Undergraduate Research in integrative research:
Steven Cregan, Garrett Haas, Gage Jackson, Patrick McDonald
Project Title: Put-A-Tag: A Generic Tagging Tool
Faculty Mentor: Dr. Cui Yu
Christopher Del Fattore, Bruce Lukens, Jesse Rosero
Project Title: The Mark: A Commenting Application
Faculty Mentor: Dr. Cui Yu
They received the awards at the University’s Annual Student Research Conference, sponsored by the School of Science.</description></item><item><title>Team of Current and Former CSSE Dept. Students Wins 24-Hour Hackathon To Benefit Jersey Shore Recovery From Super Storm Sandy</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#hackathon0413</link><description>On April 28-29, three of our Monmouth CSSE students participated in–and won–a 24-hour Hackathon called the Jersey Shore Comeback-A-Thon. Gary Kagan is currently an undergraduate Software Engineering major at Monmouth University, and Cory Cardio received his MS last year. Together with Margaret Kim, also a past CSSE student, they formed “Team Mango” and worked through the night on Saturday, developing a new and novel mobile app.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineering Dept. Graduate Reflects On MU Experience</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#vDesai</link><description>Software Engineering Dept. graduate (2012) Vishruti Desai wrote a graduation essay that appeared in the Asbury Park Press on January 19, 2013.
(Excerpt:)
I joined MU in fall 2011 to study MS in software engineering. I am glad that I selected software engineering at MU.
I am very much thankful to Dr. Daniela Rosca for providing me guidance on choosing the MS course.</description></item><item><title>Software Engineering Dept. alumnus named ‘Modern-Day Technology Leader’</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#jWormley</link><description>US Army CERDEC Release No.: 130102
14 January 2013
Monmouth University alumnus named ‘Modern-Day Technology Leader’
ABERDEEN PROVING GROUND, Md. — Jarad Wormley has been named a Modern-Day Technology Leader by the Council of Engineering Deans of the Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Lockheed Martin Corporation, and the US Black Engineer &amp; Information Technology magazine. Jarad graduated from Monmouth University in 2010 with a Masters in Software Engineering.
Jaradâs accomplishments as a computer engineer for the U.S.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Publishes A New Book</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#mob010413</link><description>“Handbook of Green Information and Communication Systems” 

(Excerpt:)
Monmouth University is proud to announce that Dr. Mohammad S. Obaidat, a world renowned scientist/engineer/academic and professor of computer science and software engineering, has published a new book titled “Handbook of Green Information and Communication Systems,” published by Elsevier.</description></item><item><title>CSSE Department Hosts its 1st Annual First Year Students Breakfast </title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#firstYearBreakfast2012</link><description>The CSSE Department held its 1st Annual First Year Students Breakfast on Tuesday, Sept 11. First Year Computer Science and Software Engineering Majors gathered to meet each other, to hear important information about the CSSE Department and to get advice about being a student and a professional in CS and SE.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Wins Prestigious SCS Presidential Award</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#mob032912</link><description>(Excerpt:)
Monmouth University is very pleased to announce that Dr. Mohammad S. Obaidat, professor of computer science and software engineering, has been awarded the Society for Modeling and Simulation International’s (SCS) prestigious Presidential Service Award.
The Board of Directors of SCS approved this award in its meeting on Sunday, March 25, 2012.
The Chair of the SCS Awards and Recognition Committee Tuncer I.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Featured In Asbury Park Press Article On Digital Reading Devices</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#mobApp0312</link><description>Computer Science and Software Engineering Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat was featured in the Asbury Park Press on 2/25/2012.
(Excerpt:)
Mohammad S. Obaidat, a professor of computer science and software engineering at Monmouth University and the editor-in-chief of several technical journals, said early predictions of a paperless culture were just premature, not wholly inaccurate. A Business Week article in June 1975 offered diverging views on the paperless office, an early mention of the concept.</description></item><item><title>CS Alumnus Featured in School of Science Newsletter</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#barnathan1</link><description>Michael Barnathan (BSCS, 2006) is the featured alumnus in the Spring 2012 issue of Science Buzz, the School of Science e-newsletter. Michael is currently a software engineer with Google, where he works on the internal development tools used to build and test Google’s software. He earned a PhD in Computer and Information Sciences at Temple University in 2010.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Publishes Two Books, Gives Two Keynote Speeches, and Receives an Award</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#obidat1</link><description>Monmouth University is proud to announce that Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat (IEEE Fellow and SCS Fellow) of the Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering has published recently two books: Pervasive Computing and Networking (Wiley 2011) and Cooperative Networking (Wiley 2011). Both books can serve as excellent textbooks for graduate and senior undergraduate courses.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Receives “Best Paper Award” at IEEE International Conference</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#obidat2</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat received the Best Paper Award from the 2011 Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) International Conference on Data Communication Networking (DCNET 2011) for his paper titled “Computational Intelligence applied to wildfire prediction using wireless sensor networks.</description></item><item><title>CS Alumnus Successfully Defends Ph.D. Thesis</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#rkhPhD</link><description>We congratulate Raffi Khatchadourian, who completed his B.S. in Computer Science at Monmouth in 2004. Raffi has successfully defended his Ph.D. thesis at Ohio State University’s Department of Computer Science and Engineering. He also earned his M.S. in Computer Science at Ohio State. His Ph.D. dissertation work was done under the supervision of Dr. Neelam Soundarajan, and the thesis was titled Techniques for Automated Software Evolution.</description></item><item><title>Professor Paparella Visits Abu Dhabi in Her Role as Executive Director of the International Council in Innovation in Higher Education Conference</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#mpaAbuDhabi</link><description>Professor Maureen Paparella presented Dr. Youssef Shatilla, a professor of nuclear engineering and associate dean of the Masdar Institute of Science and Technology, with an award of recognition for his contributions to the ICIE 2010 Conference in Masdar City, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates, in March 2011. Professor Paparella also toured Phase I of Masdar City, the world’s first “post-petroleum” city during her visit. Also receiving awards of recognition were Dr.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Gives Main Distinguished Keynote Speech at GreenCom 2010 and CPSCom 2010 in China and Receives Prestigious IEEE Outstanding Leadership Award </title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#mobGreenCom10</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat gave the main Distinguished Keynote Speech at the Joint 2010 IEEE/ACM International Conference on Green Computing and Communications (GreenCom 2010) and the 2010 IEEE/ACM International Conference on Cyber, Physical and Social Computing (CPSCom 2010) held in December 2010 in Hangzhou, China. His keynote speech was titled “On the Recent Trends and Challenges in Green Information and Communication Technology and Samples of Our Recent Research Works.</description></item><item><title>Professor Milewski Receives Bright Idea Award</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#amiBrightIdea</link><description>Professor Allen Milewski received a Bright Idea Award for co-authoring the paper titled “Occurrence and effects of leader delegation in virtual software teams,” published in the International Journal of e-Collaboration. The award is sponsored by the Stillman School of Business at Seton Hall University, New Jersey Business magazine, and the NJPRO Foundation–the public policy research affiliate of the New Jersey Business and Industry Association (NJBIA).</description></item><item><title>Professor Wang Visits Schools in Hyderabad, India</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#jwaHyder</link><description>Professor Jay Wang, Chair of the Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, visited Hyderabad, India for student recruitment on October 8 and 9, 2010. He was invited by Dr. K. V. J. Rao, the Principle of St. Peters Engineering College, which has a memorandum of understanding (MOU) with Monmouth University. Prof. Wang gave a presentation to about 350 students at St.</description></item><item><title>Professor Kretsch Gives Presentation at the Science &amp; Engineering Learning Center in Manalapan H.S.</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#jkrSELC</link><description>Professor Jamie Kretsch attended an Open House at the Science &amp; Engineering Learning Center (SELC) in Manalapan H.S. (Freehold Regional H.S. District) on Thursday 9/30. This program was for students interested in applying to the Learning Center, and was very well attended. The SELC accepts about 24 students each year, and they anticipate receiving 150+ applications. Prof.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Gives Main Distinguished Keynote Speeches at Well-Known International Conferences and Chairs Major International Conferences</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#mobsu2010</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat gave the main Distinguished Keynote Speech at the IEEE International Conference on Information Technology Convergence and Services (ITCS-10) that was held in Cebu, Philippines from August 11-13, 2010. His keynote was entitled: “Advances in the Security of e-Systems and Computer Networks.” Dr.</description></item><item><title>CS-298: Summer Study Abroad Class in Xi’an, China, June 4-15, 2010</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#cs298su10</link><description>A special topic summer travel class, CS-298 Technology in China, took place in Xi’an, China, from June 4 through 15. The class was hosted by Xi’an University of Posts and Telecommunications (XUPT), one of our MOU partners in China. Prof. Jiacun Wang developed and supervised the class. Seven undergraduate students from the School of Science, Leon Hess Business School, and Wayne D. McMurray School of Humanities and Social Sciences joined the trip.</description></item><item><title>Summer Computer Camp at Monmouth University </title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#compcamp2010</link><description>For the sixth summer in a row, Monmouth University has offered a cutting-edge Computer Camp for students in middle school and high school. This camp, directed by Shauna Schubiger is taught by professors from the Software Engineering and Computer Science Departments. It is designed to provide advanced learning in computer skills, encourage teamwork, and promote creative thinking.</description></item><item><title>Professor McDonald Publishes Book Titled Managing the Development of Software Intensive Systems, John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#jmcWiley2010</link><description>The book is a primer on managing software-based development projects and complex software/hardware systems. The book discusses the application of project management and general management techniques to large software development projects and complex software/hardware systems. This practical guide allows readers to reliably develop large software applications and systems that require the simultaneous development of electronic hardware and the software that controls the hardware.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Publishes Book Titled Fundamentals of Performance Evaluation of Computer and Telecommunication Systems, John Wiley &amp; Sons.</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#mobWiley2010</link><description>The book, co-authored by Dr. Noureddine A. Boudriga, is considered the only singular, all-encompassing textbook on state-of-the-art technical performance evaluation of computer and telecommunication systems. It has already been adopted for courses by several universities worldwide. It is the only available technical book to treat computer and telecommunication systems as inseparable issues. The authors explain the basic concepts of performance evaluation, applications, performance evaluation metrics, workload types, benchmarking, and characterization of workload.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Gives Main Distinguished Keynote Speech at IEEE ICUT 2009 Conference in Japan, and Invited Distinguished Keynote Speech at Korean Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#mobIcut</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat gave the main Distinguished Keynote Speech at the IEEE International Conference on Ubiquitous Information Technologies and Applications (ICUT 2009) that was held in late December 2009 in Fukuoka, Japan. His keynote was titled “Trends and Challenges in Wireless Networking.” ICUT is a major international conference on ubiquitous computing and communication that promotes discussion and interaction among academics, researchers, and professionals worldwide in this fascinating technology.</description></item><item><title>CS511 Students Produce Digital Campus Map</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#mkocs511</link><description>A group of students from Professor Kosaka’s CS511 Technical Communication class has produced a digital campus map that is integrated with a number of information sources deemed useful for a university community. The digital campus map is designed and implemented for a campus of small to medium size such as Monmouth University. The integration of information is independent of the size of the organization.</description></item><item><title>Computer Science and Software Engineering Dept. Signs Memorandum of Understanding with Xi’an University of Posts and Telecommunication</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#MOUXian</link><description>Dean Palladino and Xiaozheng Wen of Xi’an University
On December 5, 2009, Xiaozheng Wen, Vice President of Xi’an University of Posts and Telecommunication, visited Monmouth University to sign a Partnership Agreement between Monmouth University and Xi’an University. Monmouth University and Xi’an University of Posts and Telecommunications have agreed to engage in joint research projects, foster the exchange of academic publications and information, and promote other academic activities.</description></item><item><title>Computer Science and Software Engineering Dept. Signs Memorandum of Understanding with St. Peter’s Engineering College in Hyderabad, India</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#MOUStPete</link><description>Vijaypaul Reddy of St. Peters Engineering College and Dr. Robert McCaig
On December 4, 2009, Mr. Vijaypaul Reddy, Secretary/Director of St. Peters Engineering College, visited Monmouth University to sign a Partnership Agreement between Monmouth University and St. Peters Engineering College. The foundation of this partnership is to increase the enrollment in our Computer Science and Software Engineering programs and to develop a cultural exchange between students and faculty. Dr.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Wins IEEE GLOBECOM 2009 Best Paper Award for Paper Titled “Cross-Layer Based Data Management in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks” </title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#MobGlobeCom</link><description>The paper has been accepted in the IEEE GLOBCOM 2009 Conference, Honolulu, Hawaii, November 30 through December 4, 2009. This is one of 14 best papers that received the awards out of 1,204 papers accepted at IEEE GLOBECOM 2009. These papers were selected through a rigorous process involving symposium co-chairs, Technical program committee and reviewers recommendations, as well as the best paper selection committee of the overall conference.</description></item><item><title>Professor Wang Visits Five Institutions in Four Cities in China for Student Recruitment and Student and Faculty Exchange.</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#JwaChina</link><description>From October 22 through November 1, 2009, Professor Jiacun Wang, Chair of Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, visited five institutions in four cities in China for student recruitment and student and faculty exchange. The five visited institutions are Jiangsu Teachers University of Technology (Changzhou), Nanjing University of Science and Technology (Nanjing), Xi’an University of Posts and Telecommunications (Xi’an), Guangdong University of Technology (Guangzhou), and Guangdong University of Business Studies (Guangzhou).</description></item><item><title>Professor Kosaka Gives Talk on the “Analysis of Wishes” at Computer Science Academy, Freehold High School.</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#MkoFreehold</link><description>Professor Michiko Kosaka gave a talk to the students at the Computer Science Academy, Freehold High School, on October 26. The talk was entitled “Analysis of Wishes,” based on the work done at the University of Wisconsin. The data came from the actual New Year’s wishes (100,000 wishes) collected by the Times Square Alliance in December of 2007, who produces the famous New Year’s Eve Ball Drop.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Receives SCS Most Prestigious McLeod’s Award for Outstanding Technical Contribution and Services to Modeling and Computer Simulation</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#MObMcLeod</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat has been awarded the Society for Modeling and Simulation International (SCS) most prestigious award, the McLeod Founders Award for Distinguished Service to the Profession, in recognition of his outstanding technical and professional contributions to modeling and simulation. The McLeod Founders award has been given only six times in the 57 years of the society’s existence.</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Elected President of the Society for Modeling and Simulation International and Received Best Paper Award</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#MObSCSPres</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat was elected the new president of the Society for Modeling and Simulation International (SCS). In addition, he received the best paper award on his original research paper titled Adaptive Learning System For Congestion Avoidance in Wireless Sensor Network, accepted in the IEEE International Conference on Computer Systems and Applications, AICCSA 2009.</description></item><item><title>Departments of Computer Science and Software Engineering Merged</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#CSSEMerger</link><description>To better manage and market our CS and SE programs, the Department of Computer Science and Department of Software Engineering were formally merged into the Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering on July 1, 2009. Prof. Jiacun Wang is the new department chair, Prof. Allen Milewski is the CS/SE undergraduate program director, Prof. Cui Yu is the CS graduate program director, and Prof. Daniela Rosca is the SE graduate program director.</description></item><item><title>Graduate Program Changes Starting Academic Year 2009</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#GradChanges2009</link><description>We would like to detail changes to the Graduate CS Program starting in the Fall 2009 semester.
The MS Degree will now require 30 credits (10 courses) for students with an adequate CS background (those who do not need to take any bridge courses). These students will be able to finish the degree in 1 calendar year (2 semesters and 1 summer).</description></item><item><title>Significant CS Program Changes Starting Academic Year 2008</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#Changes</link><description>We would like to announce two recent program changes starting in the Fall 2008 semester.
First, our initial instructional programming language has been changed to Java from C++ for both the B.S. and M.S. programs.</description></item><item><title>CS Students Present Research At Seventh Annual STE Student Research Conference</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#Conference</link><description>Two CompSci students presented posters at the Seventh Annual STE Student Research Conference. Julian Montefusco, a M.S. student, presented work that she did with Dr. Yu. The title of her poster was Enhanced B+-Tree with Dynamic Node Popularity Caching. Alex Karpodinis, a senior in CompSci, presented work that he is developing as an intern at the MU Rapid Response Institute. The title of his poster was CAPer: A Dynamic XML Software Solution.</description></item><item><title>CS Alumnus Makes Successful Ph.D. Dissertation Defense</title><link>https://www.monmouth.edu/department-of-csse/news-events#sObeidatPhD</link><description>Congratulations to Suhaib Obeidat, who completed his M.S. in Computer Science at Monmouth in 2001 under the supervision of Dr. Obaidat. Suhaib has successfully defended his Ph.D. dissertation at Arizona State University’s School of Computing and Informatics. His M.S. thesis topic at Monmouth was “Performance Evaluation of Adaptive ABR Voice over ATM Networks”. His Ph.D. dissertation work was done under the supervision of Dr. Violet R.</description></item></channel></rss>